Daniel Kneipp

DevOps Engineer

9

Contact

119 Gloriosa St, Belo Horizonte, MG 305190-490, Brazil



+55 (31) 9-9605 3234 daniel.kneipp@ outlook.com



in://daniel-kneipp github://DanielKneipp gitlab://DanielKneipp

Languages

Brazilian Portuguese
[Mother tongue]
English
[Professional working proficiency]

Programming

Python, Bash, C++, Go, R

Skills

Cloud Infrastructure:



Machine Learning:

0000

Computer Vision:

Back-end Dev:



About me

I'm a DevOps Engineer with over 7 years of professional experience working with Computer Vision, Machine Learning and Cloud Infrastructure. I also have a Master's degree in Computer Science to aggregate theoretical knowledge to the practical experience.

Currently I'm working as a Site Reliability Engineer (SRE), designing cloud architectures for microservices workloads and guiding teams of Developers and new DevOps Engineers to deliver robust software and maintain high available services.

Experience

2019-Now Site Reliability Engineer

MOST Specialist Technologies

- Designed automated packing and testing processes of containerized services with Gitlab pipelines, improving update rate from weakly to daily;
- Blue-Green deployments and Rolling releases with AWS EC2, Fargate, ECS and CloudFormation;
- Deployed and maintained a monitoring system and request tracing with Elastic Stack (Elasticsearch and Kibana), reducing the time of incident response from hours to minutes;
- Infrastructure automation using Ansible to configure ephemeral development instances, Packer for automated AWS AMIs creation and Terraform for the infrastructure provisioning.

2017-2018

Machine Learning Engineer

MOST Specialist Technologies

- Developed ML algorithms for document detection in images and ID recognition (demo available at mostgi.com);
- Developed back-end services in Python and Go to serve real-time inferences.
- Worked with document classification and clustering using its textual content;

2016-2017 Computer Vision Researcher

Invent Vision

Deep Learning research for Computer Vision applications. Implemented a set of tools to speedup the development (including synthetic dataset generation) and deployment of image classifiers in embedded systems (NVIDIA Jetson).

2015–2016 Computer Vision Intern

Invent Vision

Research and provisioning of distributed computing systems (based on Hadoop and Spark), developing simple applications made to run across clusters.

2013-2014 Undergraduate Researcher

Invent Vision

Development of an efficient drowsiness detector based on face expressions (using face and eye tracking algorithms). Deployment made on x86 computers and ARM embedded systems.

Education

2016-2018

Master of Science Federal University of Minas Gerais (UFMG)

Comptuer Science — NanoComp lab. member (http://www.nanocomp.dcc.ufmg.br/). My research area was DNA Computing. The objective was to propose functional chemical circuits for classification tasks using Chemical Reaction Networks theory as a programming language and DNA strands as the hardware. One of the results of my research is a R package to simulate logic circuits based on DNA. See https://github.com/DanielKneipp/DNAr to know more

2012–2015 **Bachelor** of Science

Computer Science

I received the Presidente Bernardes Medal for my academic excellence. In my undergraduate thesis I developed an algorithm based on a bio-inspired meta-heuristic to solve a combinatorial optimization problem.

Awards

2015 University Medal

Federal University of Viçosa

The *Presidente Bernardes* Medal is awarded to students with academic excellence.

2019 **Honorable Mention** Symposium on Circuits and Systems Design Award given on the 32nd SBCCI for the work titled "DNAr-Logic DNA circuit design library in R language for molecular computing".

Communication skills

2017 **Oral Presentation**

Evostar Conference

Presented the research I conducted to obtain my Bachelor's degree. It was about the usage of Genetic Algorithms to optimize and solve a multi-component combinatorial problem.

Publications

Articles in journals

DNAr: An R Package to Simulate and Analyze CRN and DSD Networks

Daniel K. S. Vieira, Marcos V. Guterres, Renan A. Marks, Poliana A. C. Oliveira, Maria C. O. Fonte Boa, Omar P. Vilela Neto

ACS Synthetic Biology 9.12 (2020) pp. 3416-3421. 2020

Algorithm Selection in Adversarial Settings: From Experiments to Tournaments in StarCraft Anderson Rocha Tavares, Daniel Kneipp S. Vieira, Tiago Negrisoli Oliveira, Luiz Chaimowicz IEEE Transactions on Games (2018). Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE), 2018

A Comparison of Algorithms for Solving Multicomponent Optimization Problems
Daniel Kneipp Sa Vieira, Marcus Henrique Soares Mendes
IEEE Latin America Transactions 15.8 (2017) pp. 1474–1479. IEEE, 2017

Conferences/proceedings

DNAr-Logic: A Constructive DNA Logic Circuit Design Library in R Language for Molecular Computing

Renan A. Marks, Daniel K. S. Vieira, Marcos V. Guterres, Poliana A. C. Oliveira, Omar P. Vilela Neto *Proceedings of the 32nd Symposium on Integrated Circuits and Systems Design*, 2019, São Paulo, Brazil

A Genetic Algorithm for Multi-component Optimization Problems: The Case of the Travelling Thief Problem

Daniel KS Vieira, Gustavo L Soares, Joao A Vasconcelos, Marcus HS Mendes European Conference on Evolutionary Computation in Combinatorial Optimization, 2017